Guide to the Daily / Hart Family Papers, 1911-2015 MS 893
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Daily / Hart Family Papers
1911-2015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Daily, William
MS 893
2.25 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
The collection consists of four boxes containing family materials and synagogue/organization materials from Congregations Beth Israel, Emanu El and B'nail B'rith, including certificates, contracts, correspondence, school materials, reports, photographs, scrapbooks and memory books, and memorabilia spanning the years 1911 to 2015.
Biographical / Historical
Abe Daily was born January 17, 1927, in Simonton, Texas, to Lizzie and Abe Daily, Sr. Abe grew up in Simonton and graduated from San Jacinto High School. He went on to attend summer classes at Texas A&M where he learned to classify, buy, and sell cotton to work in the family business in Simonton. Abe was stationed at Fort Ord and Fort Lawton while he was serving in the U.S. Army from 1945 to 1947. Able later graduated from the University of Houston College of Optometry in 1961.
Cacilie Daily was born October 31, 1931, in Houston to Elsie and Hyman Hart. She grew up in the Southampton neighborhood of Houston and graduated from Lamar High School. She started a small business in 1980, called Miscellany.
After meeting on a blind date in 1948, and the two married in December 1950, and settled in Simonton. The couple had four children, traveled extensively after retiring, and were married for 68 years. Cacilie died in April 9, 2019, and Abe followed on July 24, 2019. They were interred at Emanu El Memorial Park in Houston.
Congregation Beth Israel was founded in 1854 as an Orthodox Jewish kehilla and is the oldest Jewish congregation in Texas. In 1874 the congregation voted to change their affiliation to Reform Judaism, sparking the foundation of Congregation Adath Yeshurun, now known as Congregation Beth Yeshurun.
In 1943 Temple Beth Israel announced that people who espoused Zionist ideals were not allowed to be members, so Congregation Emanu-El was formed by people who disagreed with that decision. As of 1967 Beth Israel accepts people with Zionist beliefs.
Excerpted from: https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/198258553/cacilie-emma-daily https://www.dignitymemorial.com/obituaries/houston-tx/abe-daily-8789203 https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Congregation_Beth_Israel_(Houston)
Scope and Contents
Four boxes containing certificates, construction contracts and blueprints, correspondence, school materials, reports, photographs, scrapbooks and memory books, and memorabilia spanning the years 1911 to 2015 document the lives of the Daily / Hart family. Of particular interest is the 1944 Annual Report from Congregation Beth Israel that douments a split in the congregation after Beth Israel announced that people who expoused Zionist ideals were not allowed to be members, which caused members who disagreed with that decision to splinter off and form Congregation Emanu El. Also included in the collection is the complete Beth Israel information packet regarding the "Basic Principles" -- or the exclusion of members with Zionist ideals -- to be voted on by the congregation.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in five series as follows: Series I: Hart Family; Series II: Daily Family; Series III: Synagogue/Organization Materials; Series IV: General; Series V: Oversize Series VI: Ironwork designs (small) Series VII: Drawings from Weber Iron & Wire Company
Immediate Source of Acquisition
William Daily donated the materials in August 2019.
Conditions Governing Access
The material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586. Allow 24-hours to recall boxes from offsite.
Related Materials
Congregation Emanu El Collection, MS 726
Separated Materials
The following books were removed from this collection and catalogued separately: The Jews in Texas by Rabbi Henry Cohen - F395.J5 C627 1895 In Good Taste - TX724 .I5 1956 Better Than Take Out: Easy Recipes for Busy Families - TX724 .B484 2004 The Jewish Texans - F395.J5 I57 1974 Talmud-Spruche - BM517.M77 G4 1906 The Scripture Stories Retold for Young Israel - BS551 .S49 1918 Introduction to the Bible: Ten Commandments and Holydays - BM105 .A47 1926 El Oroso (1944) - LD7501 .S26 076
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life; Church bulletins; Religion
Document Types
Albums (Books); Correspondence; yearbooks; Records (documents); photographs; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Autobiographies; reports; Programs (Publications); directories
Subjects (Persons)
Daily, William
- Series I: Hart Family, 1931-1977
  - Sub-series A: Cacilie Emma Hart Daily
    - Birth Certificate, 1931-10-31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Report Cards, 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Membership cards and certificates, 1944-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Lamar High School - report card, senior dance card, commencement program and diploma, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Lamar High School Yearbook, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Volunteers for Vision, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letter from White House Director of Scheduling, 1977-03-22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sub-series B: Other Hart Family
    - Correspondence between Hart family and relatives in Palestine, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Hyman Hart, invoice from H. J. Cohn Furniture Company, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - General correspondence, 1941-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Elsie (Mrs. Hyman) Hart correspondence and resume, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Elsie (Mrs. Hyman) Hart group photographs (2), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II: Daily Family, 1934-2012
  - Sub-series A: Abe Daily Jr. & Cacilie Hart Daily
    - Diploma, San Jacinto High School, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Infantry Training Certificate, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Readings from the Holy Scriptures (Army Bible), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Honorable Discharge and military information, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - University of Houston diploma and graduation materials, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Abe & Cacilie Daily photographs (6), c. 1940s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Book - Abe and Cacilie Daily, "Memories of Our Wedding,", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - News Clippings, 1950-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Abe Daily Jr., University of Houston Optometry certificate, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Abe Daily Jr., Optometry certificates and correspondence, 1963-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - San Jacinto High School Class of 1944 50th Reunion, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Invitation to Daily 50th Wedding Anniversary Celebration, 2000-12-30 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Abe Daily Jr., memoirs, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series B: Other Daily Family
    - Correspondence, Louis Daily - Jesse Jones correspondence re: immigration case of Herschl Delitizki, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Daily Bros. General Store (Simonton) materials, 1937-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Photographs, c. 1940s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Photographs, CHD-AD Rehearsal Dinner, 1950-12-28 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Membership cards, Abe and Cacilie Daily, 1950-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mexico shopping receipts, Abe and Cacilie Daily, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Congratulations and Holiday cards to Daily family, 1954; 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - William Daily, "My Bar Mitzvah" album, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Invitation, Wedding of Elizabeth Daily and Harvey Cohen, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letter from Cacilie Daiy re: ancestors buried in Louisiana, c. 2012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Abe Daily Sr., biographical information, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series III: Synagogue/Organization Materials, 1911-2015
  - Sub-series A: Congregation Beth Israel
    - Directory, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Basic Principles," information packet and voting card, 1943-11 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1944 Beth Israel Annual Report with correspondence between Rabbi Roy Walter and Cacilie Daily, 1944-2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Cacilie Hart's confirmation program, 1947-05-24 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sub-series B: B'nai B'rith - Houston
    - News Clipping, B'nai B'rith Convention, 1911-04-23-1911-04-24 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Membership card belonging to Hyman Hart, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Houston Lodge No. 434 and Herzel Lodge No. 608 events, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Event Program, First Summer Social, Galveston TX, 1938-07-31 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Program and Proceedings, Grand Lodge #7, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Houston Lodge No. 434 By-Laws, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - B'nai B'rith Women materials, 1942-1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Group photograph, Grand Lodge #7, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - B'nai B'rith Girls members' manual, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - London vacation materials, 1941-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Douglas Loeb AZA yearbook, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Sub-series C: Congregation Emanu El
    - Correspondence, Rabbi Robert Kahn (Chaplain), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bulletins, 1957; 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "David's Bar Mitzvah," text by Rabbi Robert Kahn, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Daily family certificates and report cards, 1963-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Confirmation programs, 1968; 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Commemorative programs, 1969-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Booklet, Yom Kippur services, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series IV: General, 1933-1977
  - "Jews in America" by the Editors of Fortune, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Directories, Longfellow Elementary School, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Bellaire High School graduation materials, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "50 Years Ago in Houston," Finger's Furniture Company, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Helpful Information for Every, Young Mother," Houston Chronicle pamphlet, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Coupons, Great Charity "Chaye Olam" Institutions of Jerusalem, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Series V: Oversize, 1949-1978
  - Panoramic photograph, 1949 Lamar High School graduating class (Map-drawer 189, Folder 4)
  - Architectural plans and construction contract for the Daily residence in Simonton TX, 1955 (Map-drawer 189, Folder 4)
  - Confirmation Scrapbook, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Cap, Abe & Lizzie Daily Park - Simonton Texas, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Abe Daily Jr./ Lynn Ray correspondence and legal documents, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Warranty Deed, Cacilie Hart Daily, Harris County, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photograph, Pauline (Lechenger) & Gerard Morgenstern, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - B'nai B'rith Women, certificate for Elsie Hart, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet, B'nai B'rith, "I'm Glad I'm An American", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Copy of group photograph taken at the Simonton Community Church, c. 1940s (Box 4, Folder 6)